Lori Ross

PHONE: (601) 918-8146

EMAIL: LAROSS70@GMAIL.COM

CAREER EXPERIENCE PROFILE

ACCOUNT ANALYSIS & RECONCILIATION PROFESSIONAL

Experienced AR professional with strong experience in the review, analysis, reconciliation, and remediation of outstanding supplier and customer AR accounts associated with the order to cash process. Core areas of expertise include:

- Financial Accounts Forensic Analysis
- Financial Performance Analysis & Reporting
- SAP Finance and Controlling Software (FICO)
- Reporting & Analytics Software (MS Excel, Business Objects)
- Financial Consolidation and Closing
- Financial Budgeting and Forecasting
- Vendor Management
- SOX Compliance Requirements

EDUCATIONAL CREDENTIALS & PROFESSIONAL DESIGNATIONS

- Masters of Science, Accounting Phoenix University (2010)
- Masters of Business Administration Belhaven College (2005)
- Bachelor of Science Eastern Michigan University (1993)
- Six Sigma Greenbelt (2014)
- SMU Coding Bootcamp (In Progress)

PROFESSIONAL CAREER HISTORY

McKesson Corporation

Irving, TX

Fortune 10 healthcare company that provides wholesale medical supplies & equipment, pharmaceutical distribution, and healthcare technology solutions that serves serving more than 50% of US hospitals and 20% of physicians in the US.

AR Supplier Receivables Manager

August 2012 - Present

Provide guidance and direction to a 9-person distributed team responsible for collections and reconciliation activities for a 10 member supplier portfolio with an average AR balance of \$500M

Highlighted Accomplishments:

- ✓ Reduced outstanding AR balances for newly onboarded business unit from \$700M to \$150M within 3 months.
- ✓ Designed and facilitated implementation of process improvements to improve relationship with Government Operations team which resulted in 25% reduction in DSO for VA accounts
- ✓ Designed and Implemented process improvements in the purchase order process for VA accounts leading to a 15% reduction in work capital balances.

Sr. Credit Collection Associate

April 2010 – August 2012

Manage receivables activities and product return and credit process for RNA Accounts. Collaborate with AP, Logistics and customers to ensure proper classification and booking of account credit associated with product returns.

Highlighted Accomplishments:

- ✓ Reduced DSO greater than 60 for Rite-Aid account from \$60k to \$0 in 12 months
- ✓ Provided subject matter expertise to new account onboarding process improvement effort.
- ✓ Provided subject matter expertise to team members in use of advance MS Excel functionality for aging report development and analysis.

Colemont Insurance Brokerage

Agency Associate II (July 2009 – April 2010)

Responsible for receivables and collections activities for accounts in Hartford Connecticut and Northern California geographic locations. Activities include liaison between insurance brokers and agents in resolving billing issues, process return premium refunds, issuance of direct bill commission payments (as well as collection), apply cash, collect on outstanding invoices and issue notices of cancellation when necessary. Complete month end close and prepare month end financial documents.

Blue Cross Blue Shield of Mississippi

Jackson, MS

Accounts Receivable Staff Accountant

April 2006 - June 2009

Manage receivables and billings for group accounts and nongroup subscribers, coordinate with other departments to ensure proper billing of invoices, monitor aging of receivables and facilitate resolution of outstanding balances.

Collections & Credit Billing Analyst

Feb 2005 – April 2006

Managed receivables and billings for agencies administered under the State Health Plan of BCBSMS. Line item reconciliation of membership changes to billing of 300+ agencies on a monthly basis.

Customer Service Representative

Jan 2004 – Feb 2005

Responsible for fielding telephone inquiries and solving customer concerns. Resolved customer issues related to membership, billing, and claims inquiries.

Henkel Consumer Adhesives

Avon, OH

Credit & Collections Associate II (June 2001 – Dec 2003)

Managed the initial research, and final processing of deductions for Mass Market, Food and Commercial Office Product retail chains. Interacted with external customers to resolve open deduction issues. Assessed credit worthiness of customer base and assisted department manager with monthly financial reporting and analysis. Activities included accounting entries and tracking of inventory returned to various warehouses.